Practical Application of Defect Opportunities
Welcome to this session on defect opportunities.
We’re going to study that by looking at the ranch here, the Golden Spur Ranch.
And look at a performance audit and management system
that has been based on defects per million opportunities.
Now, you'll recall that we looked at a simple layout. In this case, we’re looking at buildings,
rooms specifically, all the rooms that are used here
at the ranch, in various buildings.
And we have things like air conditioners, appliances,
fixtures, lighting, and so on. Roof, walls.
Those are the column variables, here where the cursor’s at and these are the rooms.
And we have some notation: clean, adjust, fix, repair, and stock.
So, these are the opportunities.
Now basically, little X’s goes in these boxes to show applicability.
Then during audit, for those where there are X’s they’re looked at and rated.
Clean, adjust, fix, replace, stock and so on.
That's done for vehicles, tools, animals, feed, tack,
fences, grounds, a lot of stuff. Pools.
Now, that basically boils down to being able to create several different kinds of metrics:
quality, safety, productivity, attendance, and savings.
Now with quality, we simply count discrepancies.
See, this is what we count for the metric.
Quality is discrepancies. Safety is incidents.
Productivity is carryovers. Now, what do we mean by that?
Those are things that didn't get fixed that were supposed to have gotten fixed.
They’re carryovers. And that's a productivity issue.
Attendance we use lost hours, hours missed.
And of course savings, the count is actions.
Now, for the base, the base is opportunity.
That's all those little cells in the matrix, we just looked at.
Every one of those is an opportunity.
Safety is actual hours. Hours is the opportunity base.
Productivity is discrepancies. How many discrepancies were carried over and not fixed.
Attendance is expected hours. That's the base.
And savings of course is opportunities. Savings opportunities.
Now, from that we weight them. In this case. Quality has a 25%.
Safety and productivity are the big hitters.
And attendance and savings is less weighted.
In turn, that helps us to form a bonus pool for the employees at the ranch.
Now the calculations are pretty simple.
Step 1 is A over B. So, we take the count over the base.
That's equal to C. We multiply C by a million. From there we see a table.
Now, if we take a look at the various categories.
In this case, buildings had 88 rows and 21 columns,
thereby forming 1,848 opportunities.
If I do that for each of the categories,
we discover a total of 6,288 opportunities
for something to go astray with respect to value here at the ranch.
Now, by keeping track of that.
For example, in March 1, 2003 goal was Five Sigma.
The baseline in March of 2001 was running about, in the audits,
about 101, or discrepancies per audit, or about 3.6 Sigma.
So, the goal for one year is to get that up to four,
and the goal, ultimately, in March 2003 was to get that to Five Sigma.
So, we wanted to make about a half a Sigma improvement in the course of one year.
And if you notice, we benchmark around here,
we do the ranch work about as good as airlines handle bags.
The key is we recognize that, and we're setting goals to become world-class
in how we operate and run the ranch.
Now again, there's another simple chart lined out, showing those things.
And we have the weekly reports, and our PPM conversion charts
showing the rates of improvement.
We started with the baseline of 3.65 Sigma, that we just saw.
We set a weekly rate of improvement of 1.8%,
in order to get us to the goal of Four Sigma at the end of 12 months.
So basically, I need to improve by about 2% weekly. That's our goal here at the ranch.
And that gives us our quality, productivity, safety, attendance charts.
In this case we’re looking at this part of the six up chart, showing four of the six key metrics.
And that is how we apply the idea of defect opportunities.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.